1/11/2018 Chuck Chau Resume

## **Chuck Chau - Walnut, Los Angeles, CA**

(626) 233-1319 ★ cchau2@gmail.com ★ https://www.linkedin.com/in/cchau2 ★ https://github.com/volkstrader/resume

Dedicated and versatile software development professional with experience in architecting, planning, coaching, and delivering innovative technology solutions. Demonstrated ability establishing iterative process to set short and long-term IT strategic plan; leading full cycle development to ensure on-time, on-target completion

- Interpreting stakeholders needs into user stories and acceptance criteria
- Giving technical advice to management team
- Hands-on coding architecture framework prototype / solution
- Writing technical documentation and user guides
- Coaching technical staffs on new technologies and processes
- Coordinating internal and external technology resources to realize deliverables

## **Core Competencies**

- Software System Architecture
- Object Oriented Programming
- IT Strategic Planning
- Microservices

- WebAPI Framework
- Continuous Integration (CI) Automation
- Application Lifecycle Management
- Serverless Design and Implementation

## **Technical Proficiencies** (5:Fluent, 4:Good, 3:OK, 2:Prior Experience, 1:Experimental)

Platforms	Windows (5), Linux (2), AWS (3), Docker (1), Team Foundation Server 2017 (TFS) (5), Git (3), Confluence (3), Jira (1), Salesforce (2)
	.Net (5) C# (.Net dotnetcore, .Net Standard), Meta-programming, Reflection, Managed Extensibility Framework (MEF), Autofac javascript (4) node.js, RxJs, AngularJS, Data-Driven-Document (D3) UML (4), Python (2), Powershell (3), Bash (1), T-SQL (4), Salesforce-Apex (2)
Databases	MS SQL Server (4), MySQL (1), DynamoDb (3), Redis (2), ElasticSearch (2), Couchbase (1), MongoDb (1), PostgreSQL (1)
AWS Services	API Gateway, Beanstalk, Cognito, DynamoDb, EC2, IAM, Lambda, RDS, KMS, S3, SNS, SQS
Services Packages	Redgate SQLClone, Redgate SQL Automation with Powershell, SVG, Google DoubleClick for Publisher (DFP), Google Analytic (Universal Analytic), Google Tag Manager (GTM), Twilio

# **Employment History**

Software Architect / Senior Software Engineer, ETC Processing Technologies LLC, Los Angeles, CA	12/2016- 12/2017
Senior Software Engineer, CoStar Group, Ontario, CA	4/2011- 12/2016
Technical Lead/Architect, Marshall & Swift/Boeckh (MSB), Los Angeles, CA	7/2010- 4/2011
Senior Software Engineer, Green Dot Corporation (GDC), Monrovia, CA	4/2008- 7/2010
Senior Software Engineer, Marshall & Swift/Boeckh (MSB), Los Angeles, CA	4/2004- 4/2008
Software Engineer, Prospect Science and Technology (PST), Rosemead, CA	9/1998- 3/2003

# **Recent Professional Experiences**

# Software Architect / Senior Software Engineer

ETC Processing Technologies LLC, Los Angeles, CA

Client API on AWS API Gateway

Architected a Client API which will allow ETC to pursue new line of security clearing business from online brokers, and integrate their trading platforms with ETC back office; pilot project for

1/11/2018 Chuck Chau Resume

exploring AWS cloud platform option

#### Continuous Integration (CI) Implementation

Defined and applied new Application Lifecycle Management process for development team (dev team), using Team Foundation Server 2017 with Git; targeted to fully automated build and deploy of both application and database changes to different environment

### IT Strategic Planning / Roadmap

CEO appointed to lead the effort to create IT Strategic Plan / Roadmap process and policy; documentation templates were created in Confluence, ready for 2018 planning System Architecture Assessment

Documented the current system architecture and proposed a next generation vision, the resulting document was used for FINRA audit

### **Tooling Assessment / Recommendation**

Identified and recommended new tooling software for Team Communication, Project Management, Application Lifecycle Management, and Development; leading to improving IT workflow and accountability

### Senior Software Engineer

CoStar Group, Ontario, CA

### **Enterprise Ecommerce Pricing Engine / Service**

Designed and implemented an enterprise solution for calculating shopping cart and generating price sheet, with multi-dimensional pricing model, discount schema, historical and future pricing support; leading to reduction in developer time consumed for pricing update from days to minutes

#### Marketplace Ad Creative Publishing 2.0

Acted in the role of technical lead to refactor ad creative editing workflow, utilized technologies, such as SVG, D3, Akamai, browser canvas; leading to improve overall performance and artifacts portability

Ecommerce tracking using Google Universal Analytics (UA) with Google Tag Manager (GTM) Designed and implemented an integrated solution to track ecommerce activities on LoopNet.com website using UA with GTM, enabling ecommerce conversion funnel analytic Marketplace Ad System powered by Google DFP

Designed and implemented an ad platform, integrated with Google DFP, for selling ad spaces on LoopNet.com

## Cityfeet.com and Loopnet.com Google Universal Analytic (UA)

Designed and implemented a solution to track user behavior data, such as clicks, social sharing, using Google Universal Analytic (UA)

## <u>Cityfeet.com Enhancements</u>

Upgrade UI framework using ASP.Net MVC 2 and improve SEO results for cityfeet.com, recovered over the impact by Google Panda update

## Recognitions

Nominated CoStar Innovation Award

CoSart Developer Conference

Winner of CosStar Innovation Challenge

CoStar Developer Conference

2012

#### **Education**

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona 1998 B.S. Computer Science